Margarita Mazo Old Believer and Molokan collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1: Festival of American Folklife, Washington, D.C.
  - Subseries 2: 1995 Festival
    - Negatives, slides, and photographic prints
      - [Smithsonian Folklife Festival], 1995, 35 color negatives (35mm); AFC 2022/003: PH011 (Box 17)
      - Smithsonian Folklife Festival, 1995, 1 color print (3.5x4 in.); 483 color prints (4x6 in.); 13 color prints (3.5x5 in.) (Box 10)
      - S. Fr. And Fest, June 22, 1995, 37 color negatives (35mm); 37 color prints (4x6 in.); AFC 2022/003: PH017 (Box 17, Box 14)
      - Washington, 1995, 37 color slides (35mm); AFC 2022/003: PH038_001 - PH038_037 (Box 15)
- Series 2: Stavropol, Russia fieldwork
  Field recordings, field notes, song analyses, and photographs from Mazo's fieldwork with Molokan communities in Stavropol, USSR (now Russia).
  - Subseries 1: August 1989 research trip
    - Audio and video
      - August 1989 Levokumskaya, August 6, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR067; Session III; 6 avg. 1989 Levokumskaia. Sobranie molokan - pryguny v dome u Repina Ivana Nikiforovicha Presviter: Samarin Timofei Ivanovich; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - 2. Novokumskoe Kumskaia Levokumskoe (?), August 6-8, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR068; Session V, Session VII, Session VIII; 2 1989 Novokumskoe Levokumskoe kumska 6 avg. 1989 Novokumskoe poselok: 1. Baiutki. Gulina Elena Kondrat'eva born 1950, 2. Spi mladenets, 3. Uzh ty dedushka (Shtozh) #1,2 - ubaukyvali #3 krichali, 4. Zharna-zharna devitsa v postu krichali, 5. Tiki-tiki tak, 5a Slova Tiki-Tiki, 6. I matushka ty moya (wedding, obgolashivanie), 7. I dedushka ty moi (pominalnyi), 8. A u nashego svata a) Slova, 9. Soloveiko ptashka, 10. Ty chernoi chernobrovyi, 11. Kak poshel zhe nash tzar (stikh o tuguanin-tiron), 12. Kak sostarilse cheloveche, 13. Shishkiu boron-dedushka pel, 15. Deda-deda kozyra (kozyra), 14. Arminin-kostik, 16. Tili-tili testo, 17. Alenuzhka skazka (fragment), 18. Zhili-byli ded s babkoi (skazka), 19. Levokumskoe 7/VIII (?) kat. Iv. Samar(?) 1923 Prichit. po s(?) (umer 20 iiunia) 2 fragmenta, 20. Kumskaia dolinia 8/8/89 Tiki-tiki tok (Mariia Matveevna Banderovskaia, 1932) ubaukyvali, 20a. slova, 21. Dozhdik dozhdik lin' ubaukyvali (a-slova), 22. Dozhdik dozhdik perestan' a-slova; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - 3. 1989 Kumskaia dol. #2, August 8-9, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR069; Continuation of Session V from Tape 2, Session IX, Session X; 1. Ne za rovniushku s obgolashivaniem), 2. Ne pov(?) (sirote) s obgolash, 3. Oi ty matushka (? Sv), 4. Vypadala poro? (krylovaia), 5. Ne bely to snegi (Ramzaeva? Anne Ill.) Slovami, 7. Oi gory gory kruti, 8. Oi za oi na gorochke, 9. Letela pava, 10. Za Kuban'iu za rekoi, 11. Voi kto kogo verno liubit (n. sluzhit? ne posade?), 12. Slushka (var.), 13. Ne bely snegi (vtroem), 14. Pohsla nasha solnyshka, 15. U ottsa bylo da u materi; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - 4 Kumskaya dolinia #3, August 8-10, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR070; Continuation of Session VII from Tape 3, Session XI, Session XII; 1. Uzh ty noch ty moia nog(?) (Ann Ill, Mar. Kondr. Mar. Matv. Kogda samomu Taskali(?), 2. Prosviatil mesiats, 3. Iz pod vysokova na kar(?), 4. Sviatitel'iu Nikole(?), 5. Svar. Obgoliashivanie(?) Ne za rovniushku + 2 obgol. + pesnia + gubnushka, 6. Gubnushka (d? bylo srazu posle 5.), 7. Zelen zelen Komareshek(?) pod plesku ( s gubn.), 8. Rita-rita-rita-ta-ta, 9. Na zheltnuiu(?) pesochku, 10. Vot tebe pesenke(?) konets, 11. Iz pod slavnogo goroda Galicha (3 bogatyria) Oi da vyidu poidu (ko? K neveste prik?), 13. Po shcher(?) Bylo(?) Po mor(?), 14. Zimushka zime, 15. Tat'iana - Tat'ianushka (Ne letai golub vysoko, na sv. u nevesty), 16. Mne ne spit'sia (so 2 str?), 17. Matushka moia obgolashivaiut (2) po mertvomu, 18. Oi ty Masha oi Mashutochka Banderovskoi Iv. Medgodyvich 1913 g., 19. Okh sinee more roz(?) Pl. 2 (Contin.), 23. Dozhniaia Govorkom, 24. Dozhniaia lin' rasmevaiut, 25. Dozhniaia lin' ubaukyvaiut, 26. Susen boron Ot khora Kumsk. Doliny, 27. Oi u molodtsa golova bolit (byl.), 28. Oi da gorochke Da na krute(?) (ob Ignate), 29. Ne za rovniushku (obgolashivaiut n?) fragment, 30. Peite vy golubi na sv. k(?) k neveste pri(?), 31. Potia nitia vy da vetry sil'nye v (?), 32. Oi u kniazia, u kniazia Volo(?), 33. (crossed out) po seniam po seniam po (?) (krylovaia), 34. Ne tuman (?) Konets zapisi; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - 5. Kumskaia dolinia #4, August 8, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR071; Continuation of Session IX from Tape 4, Session XIII; I. M. Banderovskii 10 Avg. 1989: 1. Zapuleem vsiu nedeliu Banderovskaia Iv. Mef.(?) 1913, 2. Khodil ia devochke po lesochku, 3. Ne iz sadu, bylo, sadu zelenogo, 4. Ne sadomu sadiku zelenogo, 5. Chto pri vy(?) Pri vysokom, 6. Akh tam da leteli sokoli, 7. Oi u kniazia (?) Vladimira, 8. Po shchar(?) bylo po moriushku, 9. Ne iz lesu, 10. (?) evrei-svr(?), 11. Po goram goram, 12. Oi da tekut vetertsy vetry ego gory(?), 13. Kak prishla ko mne (?), 14. A derevo derevo (krylovaia), 14a. Udalye mol(?), 15. Ne s(?)-ko ty mat' da, 16. Peite vy golubi, 17. Po sinei to more v dvoem, 18. Uzh (?) Dym (turetskaia), 20. Oi vo Vilone, 19. Ok iak ma da mne (tur) [?], 20a Slovami ko(?) Vilone (Anna Ill.), 21. Shli tolkachi? Pror(?) (poteshka?), 21a. Slovami, 22. Tiuku Tiuku (?) (baiukaiut); 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - p. Kumskaia Dolina pos. Novokumskii, February 11, 1989, August 8-12, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR072; Continuation of Session X, Session XIV, Session XVI; 10/8/89 X 11/8/89: 1. Da(?) Bypadalal por(?) Na taluiu zemliu, 2. Tiuku Tiuku, 3. Oi da na gorochki, 4. u. Mar. Kondr., 5. Bratets ty moi rodnoi slovami Ramzaeva, 6. Poidem, poidem korolevich, 7. Marusiu orpravili, 8. Poslednii (?), 8a. Staryi golos, 9. I bratets ty moi po khor., 10. S slezami razgovor o pokhoronakh, 12. O golosheniiakh Kak golosili nevestoi, 11. Bratets ty moi molodoi (poet), 12. Oi by gory moi, 13. Po shkolu(?) vozbuzhu(?), 14. A sestritsa moia liubimaia / Elesiutikova(?), 14a slovami, 14 b. Pesnia, 15. Shelkovaia v pole travushka rasstikhaetsia, 16. Kak zvonili oni zveny, 16a slovami Novokumskoe, 17. Liubimaia molo(?) Barbara Mikh. Gorina 1938, 18. Po materi - slovami, 19. V chistom pole stoit grusha zelenaia; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Novokumskaia, August 8, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR073; Continuation of XIII, Session XVII, Session XIX; 12 avg. 1989: 1. Uzhe ty chernyi cherno(?) Varvara Mikh. Gorina 1938, 2. Soloveiko Moi molodoi, 3. Zarodilas krasnaia, 4. Ai da ia-to u batiushki odna devushka byla, 5. Koli Ia-to byla da sestrinushka, 5a Slovami, 6. Uzhe ty molodos'(?) (kara?), 7. Po chernym to bylo po mortiushku, 8. Matushka moia ( na mertvyi golos), 8a S slezami, 8b. Slovami 8v Poet, 9. Razlivaisia bystrye (?), 10. Fedor Tyrnanin(?) Bokacheva Anna Fed(?) (1906), 11. Shlialsia ia volochilsia (na obmazke? Dome zapis) (?), 12. Akh nochka Temnaia noch' osenniaia (bober), 13. (?) Vecher idet pechaliushie, 14. U menia to muzh rabotiashchei bo(?), 15. Moi khoroshishki; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Levokumskoe (sobr. Molokan pryg.), August 13, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR074; Session XX; 13 avg. Levokumskoe Sobranie molokan - maksimistov v dome Kachergina Alekseia Ivanovicha Presvitr: Mikhail Ivanovich Abakumov; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Novokumskaja 13-14.08.89, August 13, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR075; Session XXII; Kogda privedet zhenikha razluchnik: 1. Ty sa(?)nik(?) A. Svet Ivanushka b. I, 2. On khodil pokha (?) Svekrov synu posle (?) (u zhen? V dome), 3. Soloveiko, 4. Vo vilone da Vilone, 5. Gulinia E. K. Odna (kak luker'ia? pela Dvoiur. Babka), 6. U Tat'iani odna do(?) S ogolash (bez slez?), 7. Ne pevili(?) (so slezami), 8. Razbival da (?) bel (?) shabra (drugoi zhachi? "kak vo slavnom bylo kon'skom gorode), 9. Chto pod grusheiu(?) pod zel. na kara(?), 10. Oi maytushka bol'no mne a. Polina i Lena b. Lena I 2 sestry v. Lena + Anast. Pushecha Tat. (?) G. (?) + Anna (?), 11. (?), 12. Turetskaia A raba ia (?) Zap. Chulina E. K., 13. (?) Laba-ka Turetsk. Chastushki; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Novokumskoe Levokumsk, August 13-17, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR076; Session XXIII, Session XXIV, Session XXV, Session XXVIII, Session XXIX; 15 avg. 1989 Novokumskoe: 1. Sizhu l v nevole Molokane postoiann(?), 2. Skripuchee Der(?), 3. Zima zimushka, 4. Iisus s uchenikami, 5. Uzhe ty sad, 6. V sadu pri doline, 7. Ryzhie rebiata, 8. Blagodat' vam I mir, 8a. II, 9. Baiu baiu(?), 10. II, 10a. II, 11. Kot(?), 12. Pokhor. Tekst golosa, 13. Odnazhdy my razmyshliali, 14. (?) poet, 15. I v tot den, 16. Ia skazal(?) sebe pri polovine dnei moikh Isaiia 38, stikh 10 (2 nachala), 17. Kak lan'(?) Zhelaet (2 nachala) pokhor, 18. Na chto dana stradaltsu(?) Svet Iova(?) 3, 19. Budem prevoznosit' tebe Isaiia 144, 20. Ibo vy k tomu prizvany Petra 2, 21 (2? Nachala), 21. Levokumskoe Ek. Iv. Plach slovami - potom (?) Transmission, 22. Novokumskoe Varv. Lena Gor(?) i matushka moia. Slovami poet Plachei so slezami, 23. Ne iz lesu bylo les(?) (1 var.), 24. Ty kuda letish (na?), 25. Chto pod iabloni, 26. Shelkovaia v pole(?) travu(?) (2 var), 27. Prosvetil ty batiu(?) (nachalo, prod. - Olia 4/2) Pl. 10 (?) Levokumske, 28. I bratets ty moi Koviashnikove Mar. (?) 1947 g. -slovami - 2 var. (bez slez). Plach Menee "trogatel'no" plach(?) Zhalobnyi(?) - 3 var. (so slezami) - slovami - slovami - pesnia; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Levokumskoe 11 Novokumskoe, August 18-21, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR077; Session XXXI, Session XXXII, Session XXXIV, Session XXXVII, Session XXXVIII, Session XXXIX; 18 avg. 1989 Levokumskoe: 1. Dushechka(?) Ty moia Evdokiia N(?) Khlystovi (po bratu?) a. slovami b. pet' na pokhod golos, 2. Diadia Vovochka Katia Khlystovia(?) 1974 g. a. slovami, 3. I dedushka ty moi Novokumskoe E. K. Chulinia(?) 1950 a. slovami b. poet (motiv Vo pole Veter veet) v. poet motiv golosheniia(?) g. plachem (fon magnit.) d. kak poiut (fon magnit.) e. plachem zh. Poet (nizko) z. poet (prosba poton?) i. poet no ukhodit strakh k. poet (est' pereryv) l. poet (prosba po ton?) m. poet n. golosit, 4. Oi da gorochke Da na krutenkoi; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Novokumskaja Kumskaja Dolina 12, August 21, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR078; Session XL; 12 Novokumskaya Kumskaya Dolina 1989. 21 avg. 1989; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Sestry Ramz(?) Miluenkin(?), S. I. Kumskaia Dol., August 21-22, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR079; Session XL continued from Tape 12, Session XLI, Session XLIII; 13. Kumskaia dolina 22 avg. 1989 (khoromy): 1. Svekrov(?) Moia likhochaia(?), 2. Oi da tianut vetritsa, 3. Tam prole zhivalia (so 2 str?) 3a. I posledniaia stro(?) (?), 4. Zagoralnaia(?) Kobyl(?) travushka(?), 5. i., 6. Oi da l da voidu (?) Za novye vorota (Anna I Katerina Ill.), 7. Oi tuman tuman tuman(?), 8. Okh matushka toshno mne, 9. Tam da prolechyvanie (sm. #3), 10. 11, 11. Vo gorode v kazan(?), 12. Khoro(?) moi khoro(?), 13. Goloshenoe po (?) (Bataeva Ser? Ill. 1923) 13a Slovami 13b Poet (kak golosit), 14. Akh chhto ne alen'kogo Tsvetochka, 15. Zagoral'sia kovyl travushka, 16. Oi da kak priekhali k molodoi vdove, 17. Tam stoiala gresh(?), 18. Soloveiko moi, 19. Prosviatil vsiaiu(?) temnuiu n(?); 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Stavro.889, August 23, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR080; Session XXVIII continued from Tape 11, Session XLV; Semen Milushkin I Evgenii(?) Bande: 1. Vsemirnuiu slavu, 2. Preide sen' zakonnaia, 3. Kako ne divimsia, 4. U zhe tebe radi, 5. V Chernom more; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Levokumskoe Novokumskoe 24/8(?), August 23-25, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR081; Continuation from Tape 14, Session XLVII, Session L, Session LI; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR082; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR083; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR084; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR085; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR086; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR087; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR088; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR089; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR090; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR091; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR092; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR093; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR094; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR095; 1 sound cassette
      - 5/VIII 89 Levokumskoe, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR096; 5/VIII 89 Levokumskoe pos. Novokumskii Samarin Timofei Ivanovich 1929: 1. Pokhorony, 2. Prigovory prygun Novokumskaia Samarin Nik. Timof. 1921 postoiannyi, 3. svad'ba, 4. Guliushki-zhene Praskov'ia Vas. 1927 Gulina Elena Kondrat'evna, 1950 1. rasskaz o svad'be -1yi den sv. -2oi den 1 Levokumskoe Novokumskoe, 5. Chtenie na sv. Poslanie Efisiana gl. 5, stikh 20, 6. Pryguny sobranie u Iv. Nik. Repina(?) (bez samogo nachala sobranie), 7. Posle sobraniia, 8. Novokumskaia Lena Gulina; 1 sound cassette
      - 6/VIII 89 Novokumskaia Lena Gulina A. M. Samarin, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR097; B storona Prodolzhenie Kumskaia dolina 7.08 Elizaveta Terent'eviia Banderovskaia: 9. O muz. Det. Instr., 10. Fedor Tiron (sviashch.) Feofan Kirs.(?) I Mar. Matveevna Banderovskie, 11. Na zare to bylo na zeriushke fragm., 12. O kara godakh Detskie pes. A storona Gulina El. Kondr. 1950. 1. O svad'be (prodolzh), 2. Skazka ob Alenushke i dr. Ivanushke (prodolzh) Samarin Aleks. Maks. (presvitr maksimist?), 3. Beseda o M. G. Rudom, 4. Ob obuchenii presvit., 5. Ob obiazan. presvit., 6. O pokhoronakh, 7. O zhenshchinakh v sobr. Baiu baiu, liuliu Tuku Tuku mak.; 1 sound cassette
      - 14 avg. 1989 Novokumskoe M. A. Podgorelov (zap. Sm. K. 10-11), 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR098; Prodolzh. Tekstov k plenke 9-10: 1. Vospeite gospodu 97, 2. Oreshek Skrypuchee derevtse, 4. Zimushka zime Razgovor ob ukr.(?), 5. Iisus s uchenikami, 6. Uzhe ty sad(?), 7. Uzhe ty volia (nachalo), 8. Pozabyt pozabroshen, 9. Ekhali kozaki. 1. Schitalsia, 2. Rasskaz o pominke(?), 3. Chto... 118, 4. Iova gl. 14, 5. Isaia 38 razzskaz o skazateliakh o kolenakh, 6. Blagodat - pet' kolen, 7. Ia (?) (?) T. I. Samarevy(?) (Levokumska), 10. Ryzhie rebiata, 11. Guliai guliai dev, 12. My sideli za ubran(?), 13. Igra kot I mysh(?), 14. Schitalka (scratched out); 1 sound cassette
      - 14 Kobzev Al.(?) Iv. Zagovory Novokumskoe, August 16, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR099; pos. Levokumskoe Samarin T. I. 15.08.89 1-12 Molitvy (zagov.) ot bessonnitsy, s glazu volosnikov sibirki, zhaby, mladen', gryzhi, porchi.(?) A. I. Kobzev, 1914 (pos. Novokumskii) 12. Komment. K zap. (?) -4, 3-13; 1 sound cassette
      - Abakumov Andrei Mik. 17 avg. (maks.) Levokumka, August 17, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR100; Abakumov Andrei Mikhailovich, pos. Levokumskii; 1 sound cassette
      - Levokumskoe (Andr. Mikh. Abak.) 17 avg., August 17, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR101; 1 sound cassette
      - pos. Novokumskoe Lena Gulina, A. I. Kobzev 7, August 18, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR102; 18 avg. 1989: 1. Levokumskoe konets razgovora o plache, Katia Khlystova 1974, 2. Novokumskoe E. K. Gulina Komm. K plenke 11, #3 -komment. K 3v(?) -plachem - poet; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Levokumskoe 20 avg. 1989 Side B: 8. Lena Gulina g. Nikulushchkina 8, August 20, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR103; Levokusmkoe 20.08.89: 1. Zapis na vykupe rubashke (svadba v dome nev.) Abakumovy -kommentarii N. M. Abak., 2. Zapis v dome zhenikha, 3. "" nevesty Vozvrashch. V d. Zhenikha (vstrecha) - psalom - pesnia; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Novokumskaia Gulina teksty 9 Side B: Sestry, August 21, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR104; Lena Gulina - teksty; 21.08.89. rassk. O sv. Prodolzh. Svadby Kumskaia dolina Ramzaeva A. I. Sanicheva K. I. Babaeva S. I. 21. 08.89: 1) Tam prolezhivala (so sl. 2 soldatushki 2 takhanskie, 2) Oi, tuman, tuman (so sl. Oi, pechal' toska), 3) Tam postroeny (tam prolezhivala) prutskaia, 4) Vo gorode bylo vo (?) (scratched out) ...est bratets "Plyvet korabl s moria" do bogatyi.. ., 5) Rep. - Ona svoi golos lomaet I (Nikulushk.) Ramzaeva, 6) Mne ne snitsia, mladtsu ne lezhitsia - fragm., 7) Chto ne alenkii tsvetochek (fragm.) A. I. Ramzaevy 22.08.89 S. I. Babaeva, 8) Kommentarii k prichit. (pl. N 13) o pokhoron., 9) razgovor o goloshchenii - A. I. Ramzaeva, K. I. Sanicheva, 10) Zagoralasia kovyl-travushka (...Vy poduitia vetry sil'nye, 11) Zhili my byli na onom svete (lazar'), 12. Ekhala belka na telezhke Sveta Dotsenko, 8 let, 13) Katilos' iablochko po ogorodu, 14) Rassk. ob igrakh A. I. Ramz. i S. I. Babaeva; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Kumskaia dolina Banderovskii Feofan. Kirs. 22 avg. 1989 10 Side B: Semen Iv. Feofan Kirs., August 22, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR105; Otets Feofan Kirsanovich Banderovskii (turetsk. Okkau? 1931 g.) 22 avg. 1989: 1. Kak glasy uchat, 2. Tyryzh(?), 3. Razgovor Komment k zapisi Sem. Iv. I Evlam(?) K(?) Feofan Kirs. Banderovskii; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: 23 avg. 1989 Kumskaia dolina Banderovskii Feofan. Kirs. 11 Side B: prodolzhenie Feofana Ramzaeva - teksty, August 23, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR106; 1 sound cassette
      - Copy of Tape 11, August 23, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR107; 1 sound cassette
      - Side B: 24 avg. "russkie mestn. (prodolzh.), 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR108; pos Novokumskii: 1. S. T. Eluplina(?) (slova placha na plenke), 2. Aksin'ia Timofeevna Pushechkina; 1 sound cassette
      - 12A Gen. Trofim. Ialuplina (Stavro. 889, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR109; Stefanida Trofimovna Ialuplina - slova obgolashivaniia: 2. Kak sostarilsia cheloveka - Aksin'ia Timofeevna Pushechkina - kak uchili skazki I dukh. Stikhi - o pokhoronakh; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR110; Kopii s magnit. Velichkinoi O.: 1. Novokumskaia - Gulina rassk. Ob obriadiakh - sil'nyi fon v nachale 1oi storony; 1 sound cassette
      - I(?)eg(?)-2 (copy), 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR111; pos. Novokumskaia Babaeva (babushka Leny Gul.) Lena Gulina teksty Varvara Chorina? Teksty I pesni Zapis' v tserkvi (Kumskoi?) Nachalo Babaevoi; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR112; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR113; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR114; 1 sound cassette
      - Copy-Ikeg(?) (O. V.) 6, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR115; Molokane svad'ba (prodolzhenie) Ikeg(?)-6; 1 sound cassette
      - Copy Ikeg(?) - 6 Molok. Svad'ba (O. V.) 7, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR116; Molokane - svad'ba prodolzhenie ( s Ikeg? Pl. 6); 1 sound cassette
      - Stavropol'e 1989 recorded by Margarita Mazo and O. Velichkina, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR117; 1 sound cassette
      - Stavropol'e 1989 recorded by Margarita Mazo and O. Velichkina, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR118; 1 sound cassette
      - Stavropol'e 1989 recorded by Margarita Mazo and O. Velichkina, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR119; 1 sound cassette
      - Levokuskoe, Samerin copy, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR120; 1 sound cassette
      - Painting a house, 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR121; Recorded on the street while 2 women painted a house.; 1 sound cassette
      - Isai Ivanovich Koveshnikov #2 Pesni Bakantsy(?), 1989, AFC 2022/003: SR122; Tape from the library of Koviashnikov Recordings of Molokans from Baky; 1 sound cassette
    - Manuscripts
      - Field trip, 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/15)
      - Molokan field notes (1 of 2), 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/1)
      - Molokan field notes (2 of 2), 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Notebook 1 Nekrasovtsy 1, 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Notebook 2 Nekrasovtsy 2, 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Notebook 3 Teksts, Nekr., Address, 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Notebook 4 Molokans 1, 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Notebook 5, 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Notebook 6, 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/8)
      - [Stavropol song transcripts and sheet music], 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/9)
      - Stavropol tape indexes, transcripts, and reports, 1989-1994, 2008-2020, afc2022003_dc001; Partial tape indexes, song transcripts, and reports from Mazo's research in Stavropol, Russia in August 1989. These indexes and transcripts were a work in progress, that Mazo continued to revise and enhance throughout her career.; 25 digital manuscripts (DOCX, WPD, PDF, ASC, RTF, TXT)
      - [Third International Scientific Church Conference], 1988, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/10)
      - [Tape indexes, Stavropol tapes 1-15], August 1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Negatives, slides, and photographic prints
      - Nekrasovtsy field, 1989, 14 color negatives (35mm); AFC 2022/003: PH024 (Box 17)
      - Stavropol, 1989, 1 color print (4x6 in.); 67 color prints (3.5x5 in.) (Box 11)
      - Stavropol, 1989, 27 color negatives (35 mm); 3 color prints (4x6 in.); AFC 2022/003: PH022 (Box 17, Box 14)
      - Stavropol, 1989, 64 color negatives (35mm); AFC 2022/003: PH023 (Box 17)
      - Stavropol Molokans, 1989, 38 color slides (35mm); AFC 2022/003: PH039_001 - PH039_038 (Box 15)
  - Subseries 2: 1990 research trip
    - Audio and video
      - Stavropol' 1990 5/4/90 Nikolai Mois. Abakumov 1926 7, May 4, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR123; 1 sound cassette
      - Kamennaya Balka, May 5, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR124; 1 sound cassette
      - Kamennaya Balka, May 5, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR125; 1 sound cassette
      - Kamennaya Balka, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR126; 1 sound cassette
      - Kamennaya Balka, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR127; 1 sound cassette
      - Kamennaya Balka, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR128; 1 sound cassette
      - 7 Konets stor. 6B, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR129; 1 sound cassette
      - Kamennaya Balka, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR130; 1 sound cassette
      - Ferma, Sara Vas Samarina, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR131; 1 sound cassette
      - Kamennaya Balka, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR132; Side A: Kam. Balka Chernikova; Side B: Kam. Balka Arzgir.; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR133; 1 sound cassette
      - Arzgir, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR134; 1 sound cassette
      - Arzgir, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR135; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: V. A. Prizernoe(?) 5-90 Stavro. Side B: Prod. Na 21(?) Nachalo Kobzevykh VA, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR136; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR137; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR138; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR139; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR140; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR141; 1 sound cassette
      - Novokumskoe Podgorelov / pust' 19, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR142; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Novokumskoe gorine 5 1990 20 Side B: 5-90 V Nekrasovtsy(?), May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR143; 1 sound cassette
      - 21. Prodolzh. Nachalo Kobzevykh storona B (?) #13a, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR144; Continuation of Sony 13A.; 1 sound cassette
      - Novokumskoe, Samarin, Kobzev, Podgereden, May 18, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR145; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: 23. Koveshnikov Iv. Iv. Prod. #9B Side B: Iv. Iv. Koveshn. (prod.), May 18, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR146; 1 sound cassette
      - Levokumskoe, Koviashnikovs, Psalm structure lament, May 19, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR147; 1 sound cassette
      - Levokumskoe; Abakumor; Koviashnikov, May 21, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR148; 1 sound cassette
      - Levokumskoe copy, May 21, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR149; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: 26. Is. Iv. 21/maia/90 Side B: Is. Iv., May 21, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR150; 1 sound cassette